Prakhyaat Rathee . Jarvis Consulting

Prakhyaat is a creative operation specialist skilled in designing and handling management information systems. He has experience in analyzing, articulating, and solving various business problems using technological solutions. He is organised professional comfortable working independently or as a part of a team.

Skills

Business Skills: understanding of capital markets, payment gateways and general banking processes, experience in procurement, managing sales pipeline and developing marketing strategies, experience working in an agile environment, good understanding of software development life cycles, agile and waterfall approaches to software development, experience in eliciting technical requirements for documentation purposes, effective communication style- both oral and written, led team projects on multiple occasions for the development of data-driven or product driven IT projects.

Technical Skills: RDBMS/SQL, Data modelling/mapping/UML diagrams/design schemas, experience in creating object-oriented design patterns, experienced in using Microsoft excel, word, access, dynamics & Power point, understanding of google cloud platforms, linux machines, and bash scripting, experience in creating system schema diagrams, activity diagrams, and data flow diagrams, experience in developing user stories and user personas., experience in using visualization tools such as Power BI and Visio.

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng PrakhyaatRathee

Linux Monitoring Agent [GitHub]: Developed a Linux cluster monitoring agent to assist Jarvis Linux admin team manage their resources effectively. Elicited technical requirements and developed scope and incorporated changes in a highly agile environment, created project charter, data flow diagrams, and system sequence diagrams, and monitored the development of the databases from scratch to collect real-time information pertinent to the CPU usage to assist the team.

Proof of concept-Stock and trading [GitHub]: Developed a requirement specification document for a Jarvis client who is in need of a mobile application for stock brokers. Developed project document, gathered system requirements, and created system specification document, also conducted brainstorming activities, interviewed stakeholders, and managed resources for the development of mobile app proof of concept as requested.

Highlighted Projects

Kill Ship: Developed a game using java BlueJ terminal to locate user ships and destroy them to win points. Key skills developed- problem-solving, understanding of classes and objects through object-oriented programming, using the concept of modularisation, and ensuring code quality is great by maintaining cohesiveness to the highest degree at class and method levels.

Fit Bit Tracker: Developed a technical document for a household client who won a lottery and wanted to launch an app fit bit tracker. Handled documentation of non-technical requirements and translated them into technical specifications for the team of developers at Monash. Key skills- Organising meetings , handling schedules, elicitation of technical requirements, and preparing iteration documents.

Professional Experiences

Business Analyst/Project Coordinator, Jarvis (09/2022-present): Conducted system analysis and implemented a Linux cluster program for Linux administrators at Jarvis, adhered to the requirements of software development life cycle in a highly agile environment, defined and documented the scope of projects for distribution within teams, planned computer systems using information engineering and structured analysis, key technologies used-docker, google cloud platform to provision Jarvis Remote Desktop, postgres SQL, shell scripting and IDE. Achievements: Successfully completed the project and was assigned the next data driven project.

Disability Employment Consultant, APM, Australia (11/2021-05/2022): Independently handled a portfolio of 84 and more clients dealing with mental issues ranging from clinical anxiety to Schizophrenia, mentored job seekers, and provided them support to develop their employability skills, recognised client employment barriers ad devised strategies to resolve those barriers by counselling and coaching, used excellent negotiation and relationship building skills to meet the program requirements set by the department and their medical practitioner. Achievements: successfully overachieved my monthly KPIs each month and earned subsequent bonuses.

Project Manager- Work Integrated learning, Australian Computer Society (06/2020-07/2021): Led the development of a chat boat for a real estate company that wanted to manage its incoming leads more effectively. Demonstrated solid leadership qualities to meet deadlines and earned a personalized letter of recommendation from the chief at ACS.

Consultant-Digital marketing, Procurement, and Sales, Best Buy Cars- Hawkins Network (10/2019-11/2021): Input analyzed and reported on data covering all aspects of operation thus ensuring data integrity is maintained, built relationships with vendors to negotiate ideal terms of purchases, provided weekly updates on digital marketing campaigns to senior managers, discussed strategic initiatives and methods of improvement, administered, supported and monitored databases by proactively resolving database issues. Achievements: supervised transitioning of records from traditional filing method to completely online using Microsoft excel.

ICT Business Analyst -professional Training, Monash University (01/2019 - 07/2019): Developed a website for tourists to help them if they get stuck in the middle of a bush fire. Planned the project approach for requirement gathering, conducted brain storming sessions, and created and developed iteration document, also developed user stories, story mapping, created use case diagrams and conceptual database schema in order to facilitate the full development of the system in an agile environment, used Kanban to facilitate inter-team discussions and managed work-flows ensured functional and non-functional testing are satisfactorily completed. Achievements-Industry student cash ward for the completed project.

Education

Monash university (2017-2019), Masters of Business Information Systems, Information technology - International Scholarship - Vice President - Monash Debate club - mentor peer group

IP university (2009-2012), Bachelor of Business Administration, Banking and Insurance - University topper - placement coordinator - student magazine editor

Miscellaneous

- International Institute of Business Analysis- entry-level certification in Business Analysis(BABOK)
- Freelance-Yoga instructor
- Reading self help books